RG 112, Plainfield Historical Society
Connecticut State Library
Plainfield Historical Society records
1820-1932
Connecticut State Library
Plainfield Historical Society (Plainfield, Conn.)
1 cubic foot
The Plainfield Historical Society was established in a meeting held January 8, 1916 in the Town Clerk’s Office, Central Village. Judge John E. Prior was chosen chairman. The date of its last meeting was November 10, 1917.
RG112
1933-001
Historical Note
The Plainfield Historical Society was established in a meeting held January 8, 1916 in the Town Clerk’s Office, Central Village. Judge John E. Prior was chosen chairman. The date of its last meeting was November 10, 1917.
Scope and Content
Records created by the Society include correspondence, financial records, reports, scrapbooks, historical sketch of the town of Plainfield, essays submitted for an essay contest, and materials documenting the Society’s reorganization in 1916-1917. Materials collected by the Society include records of North Meeting House School District (1821-1831), the Moosup School District (1831-1878), the Central School District (1829-1873), the Plainfield School Society Treasurer’s records (1833-1871), and some anonymous account books.
Related Material
None.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Plainfield Historical Society (Plainfield, Conn.)
Places:
Plainfield (Conn.)
Subjects:
Plainfield Historical Society (Plainfield, Conn.) -- Records and correspondence; Plainfield (Conn.) -- History
Document Types:
Account books; Essays; Scrapbooks; Correspondence; Financial records; Membership lists
Restrictions on Access
See the policy.
Provenance
The records pertaining to the Society, along with miscellaneous historical records which were collected by the Society, were deposited January 17, 1933, at the State Library.
Container List
- Records, 1820-1932
  - 1. Correspondence, 1915 March 14-1932 December 20; 1 folder (Box 1)
    Primarily incoming correspondence to Mr. John E. Prior, President, Plainfield Historical Society.
    Chronological.
  - 2. Records of the Society, 1916-1918 (Box 1)
    - Minutes of meetings, 1916-1917; 1 volume (Box 1)
    - List of members, 1916-1917; 1 volume (Box 1)
    - Card index of members, 1916-1918 (Box 1)
    - Officers of Plainfield Historical Society, undated; shared folder (Box 1)
    - Application for membership blanks, shared folder (Box 1)
  - 3. Financial accounts, 1916-1923, 1932 (Box 1)
    - Treasurer's account book, 1916-1917 (Box 1)
    - Check book, 1916-1923 (Box 1)
    - Receipt book, 1916-1917 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous receipts and account statements, 1916-1918, 1932 (Box 1)
  - 4. Historical data, 1916-1918 (Box 1)
    - Scrapbook of clippings about Plainfield history and participation in WWI effort, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - Historical sketch of town of Plainfield, 1 folder (Box 1)
  - 5. Essays submitted to Plainfield Historical Society essay contests, 1918; 2 envelopes + 1 volume (Box 2)
  - 6. Historical records kept by the Society, 1820-1880 (Box 2)
    - Records of meetings of civil authorities of town of Plainfield, 1826-1835, 1880; 1 volume (Box 2)
      Includes diagrams of land and buildings. Probably by Joseph A. Deane, an insurance agent in Plainfield circa 1880.
    - Records of North Meeting House School District, 1821-1831; shared volume (Box 2)
    - Records of Moosup School District, 1831-1878; shared volume (Box 2)
    - Plainfield School Society Treasurer's Records, 1833-1856; 1 volume (Box 2)
      Includes dog registration, 1865-1871.
    - Records of Central School District, 1829-1873 (Box 2)
    - "Young Reader." New York: George F. Cooledge, undated; 1 volume (Box 2)
    - Unidentified account book, 1830-1834; 1 volume (Box 2)
    - Unidentified account book, 1820-1828; 1 volume (Box 2)